Heiwa Fansubs Presents:
"Great Detective Conan"
"Challenge to Kudo Shin'ichi"
I know now.
Just why we are trapped in this room.
The criminal who did all this...
Ran...
...it was you.
That's right, Shin'ichi.
Truth is, I...
Ran! Are you okay?!
Shin'ichi?!
Damn!
Shin'ichi.
What is this?
Some gas...
Shin'ichi...
Ran...
Kudo-kun, Kudo-kun.
Are you hurt anywhere?
"High School Student Detective
Kudo Shin'ichi"
Kudo-kun.
"MPD Investigation Unit One
Takagi Wataru"
Thank goodness.
Sato-san, Kudo-kun has
recovered consciousness.
"MPD Investigation Unit One
Sato Miwako"
Both of them were found collapsed.
They're being identified right now.
"Shin'ichi's Childhood Friend
Mori Ran"
Ran...
Ran! Are you okay?
Please don't over strain yourself.
I'm fine.
Um... Could it be that Ran's been injured?
I'm sorry, but... she's dead.
Huh?
"Medical Coroner - Hirata Hajime"
For the moment, the cause of death is unknown.
After an autopsy,
I think we'll find out something.
Right away, please.
Understood.
Wait... Hold on a minute!
Please wait a minute!
Kudo-kun, do you remember who I am?
Truth is, you and I met once before
at a crime scene.
What are you talking about at a time like this?!
More importantly, Ran!
Her body has already gotten cold.
It's regrettable you and I had to
meet again in this way, isn't it?
If you would please.
Please wait!
- Ran!
- Calm down!
Ran!
Kudo-kun! Calm down.
I understand how you feel, Kudo-kun.
I understand, but...
Kudo-kun!
What you can do for Ran right now
is tell us everything you know!
Let me go!
- Come to the station with us.
- Lemme go!
Ran!
Raaan!
"Beika West Police Station"
Were there any suspicious points
at the crime scene?
Crime scene?
The place where Ran and I collapsed.
That reminds me, the ground around where Ran
had collapsed was a little wet, wasn't it?
Wet?
Kudo-kun, you haven't told us anything...
...but I think you two were carried there from
somewhere else after you had lost consciousness.
That's why Ran-chan was
the only one who was wet, right?
But the condition of the corpse
doesn't match that of someone who had drowned.
Are you okay, Kudo-kun?
Kudo-kun!
You should go to the restroom.
Kudo-kun, this way.
At any rate, for Ran-kun's sake,
we'll investigate this with all our might.
That's why, Kudo-kun...
...you should place your trust in
Sato-san and myself...
...and we hope your deposition
will advance our investigation.
"How disappointing, Great Detective, you forgot
something important at the scene of the crime"
"You forgot something at the scene of the crime"
Because you're a major witness...
...there may be police officers in here
who will say unpleasant things to you...
...but I want you to overlook it.
Whaa! Hey!
Watch it there, Kudo-kun.
I'm sorry.
Truth is, Kudo-kun, Sato-san and I...
Kudo-kun?
Kudo-kun!
Sato-san!
Kudo-kun has run off!
The major witness in
a murder case has escaped!
To repeat! The major witness in
Block all major arterial roads...
"Shin'ichi and Ran's Fellow Student
Suzuki Sonoko"
Kudo-kun, what's wrong?
What is it? Have you
gotten involved in a case again?
That's right.
Sonoko, I need a favor from you.
Without asking me anything,
could you take me to the Beika Marina?
Please.
Could it be Kudo-kun,
you're being chased by the police?
Please, help me.
Please trust me.
Leave it to me.
"Beika Marina"
I don't know what case
you've gotten yourself involved in...
...but once it's settled,
explain it all to me, okay?
Yeah. Thank you.
"How disappointing, Great Detective, you forgot
something important at the scene of the crime"
"What is it I forgot?"
"This note was clearly put into
my pocket by the criminal."
"What on earth is the criminal's goal?"
Ran...!
Damn...!
What is this about!?
"Private Detective
Mori Kogoro"
Fool! It's me, I tell you!
Stop that you fool! It's me!
Sorry! Sir, are you okay?!
Sir, how did you get out of the white room?
Well, I dunno.
I lost consciousness about that time.
When I came to, I was sleeping on
a bench in some strange park.
And, while there, a letter was left behind
telling me to come and meet you here.
"Mori Ran and Kudo Shin'ichi
are at Beika Marina"
But there were a lot of police around...
Oi...
It's a lie, right?
It's absolutely a lie that Ran is dead, right!
My daughter is...
Oi, tell me that it's a lie!
She's only 17!
What would my 17 year old daughter die from?!
Why?!
Answer me, boy detective!
That's!?
What is it?!
Ran's cell phone!
Ran's?!
It's cold...
That reminds me, that glass was clouded.
"The ground where Ran had collapsed
was a little wet, wasn't it?"
The ground was wet...
Cloudy...
A temperature difference...
A frozen cell phone!
Ran was wet.
I've got it! Flash-freezing!
The criminal in that white room
only flash-froze the room Ran was in!
It may be that Ran is still alive!
Eh?!
I've read about a state of
apparent death due to flash-freezing...
...that was researched in the past
all around the world.
They seemingly really had died...
...but when defrosted properly,
there were cases where they were revived.
Is that true!
Is it true Ran really is alive?!
"The True Criminal"
Hello...
Kudo Shin'ichi, I shall give you
one piece of information.
Who are you!?
What on earth is your goal?!
Mori Ran's autopsy...
...has been set for today at 16:00.
Eh!?
That's one hour from now.
Can you get your love back
with your own hand?
Autopsy?!
They're going to do an autopsy
on Ran even though she's alive?!
Sir, let's hurry!
Yeah!
"Beika West Police Station
Morgue"
"Beika West Police Station"
Excuse me, I caught this boy shoplifting
at Beika Bookstore, so I've brought him in.
Which floor is your
person in charge of thefts?
I'm sorry! I repent it!
You should repent!
In that case, it's on the 2nd floor.
Thank you!
Wait!
What is it?
I want to ask you something about
the security here. Is that okay?
Your mother is crying, you know!
I'm sorry!
Good job.
"Morgue"
Sir!
- Ran...!
- Ran!
Ran!
Ran...
- Sir!
- Yeah!
One, two...!
One, two!
Damn!
Calm down!
What happened on May 15th?
Oi! What kind of case was this one?
The murder case that took place in a cold storage
warehouse of a home-delivery company.
"The Medical Examiner's
investigation was wrong."
"This person was accidentally locked in the cold
storage warehouse, but didn't die by freezing."
"They had been brought to
this warehouse and then murdered."
"This is..."
"...a full-fledged murder case."
Ah, it was that case, huh?
But, I don't know what
the 6 character keyword is.
Ah!
"Kudo-kun.
Do you remember who I am?"
Sir! Do you know the name of
the Medical Examiner from that time?
If I recall...
"The Medical Examiner's
investigation was wrong."
"I thought as much myself."
Wasn't it Hirata?
He was this hugely self-confident Medical Examiner
I had met several times at case crime scenes.
Hirata...
That's right!
It was Hirata Hajime!
"Hirata Hajime"
Ran!
No, you're wrong...
This is a mannequin!
Damn!
Stop messing around!
What is this?!
What on earth is this?!
This is your fault, boy detective!
Though you were so concerned about her,
why didn't you protect Ran!
I'm sorry, Sir.
Before saying "sorry," hurry and find Ran!
You're useless!
I'll beat you to death!
Ran!!
What are you doing here?!
This is off-limits to outsiders!
I'll call for a police officer.
Don't move from there.
Huh?
Aren't you Kudo Shin'ichi-kun?
Why would a major witness to
a crime come running off to here?
What is it?
How did you know that we were here?
What are you saying?
After that huge fuss you made,
anyone would have noticed you.
Shouting out "I'll beat you to death"
like that in a police station.
What is it?
Well, because the keyword for
the final panel was your name.
Keyword?
What are you talking about?
I just happened to hear your uproar and...
We were just doing this.
"This is your fault. I'll beat you to death."
It's just I couldn't help but think that
from the wiretap device on this strap...
...we were being watched over by
the one involved in this.
"Sorry, Sir."
"Before saying 'sorry,' hurry and find Ran!"
"You're useless!"
"I'll beat you to death!"
"Ran!!"
When we found Ran's cell phone at that spot...
...I noticed that this part of
the strap had a small hole in it.
That's why we...
"Can you get your love back
with your own hand?"
"Oi!"
"Shh!"
"What's going on?"
"A wiretap has been prepared in this strap."
"Let's take advantage of the fact that
someone is eavesdropping on us, Sir."
"Autopsy!?"
"They're going to do an autopsy on Ran
even though she's alive?!"
- "Sir, let's hurry!"
- "Yeah!"
We deliberately said we were going to
the Morgue so that you would hear it.
And, before coming to this police station...
...the boy detective and I
recorded a fight scene between us.
The criminal who shut us in that white room...
...was you, wasn't it?
Medical Examiner, Hirata Hajime-san.
The criminal who shut us in that white room...
...was you, wasn't it?
Medical Examiner, Hirata Hajime-san.
Why are you talking so triumphantly for?
The situation hasn't changed in the least.
To keep a person in a state of
apparent death by hypothermia...
...it's essential to have a
delicate control over their temperature.
When I press this button,
that temperature control will be suspended.
Then, somewhere in this room,
Mori Ran will die, just as she is.
Yes, yes, that's right, Kudo Shin'ichi.
That's the expression I wanted to see.
That look of misery when
you knew you had lost.
When I met you in town a short while ago...
...you didn't even remember me.
You didn't know at all the times
your voice has run through my thoughts.
Despite appearances...
...I'd been told I was certain to be made next President
of Tokyo's Health Sciences University as an elite doctor.
I had also contributed to cases as
a Medical Examiner, which had led to arrests.
However...
...due to that cold-storage warehouse case...
...both my career and honor
were completely ruined.
Do you understand?
It's your fault my life went out of whack!
That's why you prepared that white room...
...and made me recall those cases from my past.
Since you had torn up people's lives...
...I thought it simple courtesy that you
should at least remember their names and faces.
Save Ran!
Where is Ran?!
"Please" save her, isn't it?
Use respectful language.
Do you understand the position you're in?
Damn...
Oi! Boy detective!
Don't you have any tricks up your sleeve?
No.
Oi!
Hirata-san...
This is my total loss.
So please tell me just one final thing.
How did you...
...shut us into that white room?
What's that...?
If you'd like to know,
then get on your knees and beg!
Say, "I would please like to know, Hirata-san."
I want to know...
Hirata-san...
...please...
...please tell me!
Can't be helped, huh?
Then I'll tell you.
That girlfriend of yours that
you have such total trust in...
...she gave each of you some sleeping pills.
Ran...
She gave them to us?!
I first kidnapped that girl's mother
and then frightened her.
It was easy to get her to listen then.
What?!
That's how it was...
Where is Eri-san right now?!
She's staying quietly aboard the yacht
"New Orient" anchored in Honmokufuto.
She hasn't been hurt.
About all she has is some seasickness.
That's why Ran...
Do you feel regret?
Isn't it vexing?
This isn't regret.
Huh?
I'm pissed off like crazy!
You took advantage of Ran's gentle heart...
...you bastard!!
Did you hear that?
The "New Orient" in Honmokufuto.
Please hurry!
What's that?!
Don't move.
What is this?
Your wiretap uses radio waves.
So I had Detective Sato and Detective Takagi
tap into those same radio waves.
Since when...
Kudo-kun ran by us in an all-to-obvious disguise
just as we had appeared at the police station.
That's when I was certain he wanted
our secret cooperation in something.
Once the two of them were inside...
"Don't say a word, please meet us at the stairs."
...we made contact in the hallway.
Where could Kisaki Eri-san be saved from?
Now the local police know.
Damn...
I'll press it!
Fool! That's dangerous!
Hirata Hajime! I arrest you on
suspicion of attempted murder.
Ran!
- Ran!
Ran! Ran, hang in there!
Ran...
Ran, wake up.
I...
...wasn't in time?
Ran?
Ran...
Shin'ichi?
Are you crying?
Fool.
You're the one who's crying.
Shin'ichi...
I'm sorry...
You're angry, aren't you?
I'm so angry with myself, it's unbearable.
That Ran was alone
all that time in the white room...
...and troubled the entire time.
And yet I never realized that.
I'm truly...
...very sorry.
Shin'ichi...
Still...
I'm happy that you're safe.
Dad...
Dad, I'm sorry for worrying you, too.
Ah, well... that's okay.
All that matters is that you're safe.
Eri's okay, too.
Everything will be fine now.
Everything's fine!
Then I guess I'd better go see Eri.
Thank goodness...
Okay, let's get you to a hospital.
Say, Shin'ichi.
Being a detective; you can't do anything
other than track down criminals?
I guess from here on, too...
Yeah.
I'll go on being a detective.
I have to shoulder my responsibility as
a detective for each of the cases I solve.
That's the thing I truly
came to understand today.
I see...
All right.
Ahh!
Since we were in that small place for so long...
...once you leave the hospital,
let's go somewhere wide open and party.
An amusement park!
All right, all right.
Then, once you've gotten all better...
...and won the city Karate Convention
and recovered from that...
...we'll go to an amusement park.
All right!
"Tropical Land"
"Several Months Later"
Geez!
I get invited out
by Shin'ichi and you run late.
Sorry, sorry.
It's all my treat today.
Can't be helped then.
Ran, what do you want to ride?
Of course it has to be...
For pete's sake!
I've been worried about them all this time
and they're out on a date?
Well, whatever.
No reason for me to interfere.
Go!
Ah, that's right, Ran.
Here.
"Like this, the case of
the white room was settled..."
"...Ran was back to her normal cheerfulness..."
"...and the two of us had come to
an amusement park to have fun."
I'm so happy!
"Truth is, it was there we would encounter
a shocking, big case..."
"...and I would have an outrageous experience
with some mysterious men in black..."
"Well, that's a story for another time."
There is always just one truth!
"This Drama Is Fictional"